Ajay Kumar

Security Professional,

at Reliance Industries Ltd.

Email: Join2ajkumar@gmail.com

Having 5+ Yrs. of experience in physical and automation security in the world's largest refinery with exposure to setting up control rooms, monitoring & troubleshooting alarms by Access control & Video surveillance system, emergency incident handling & investigations, guiding AMC Team & assisting employees in day to day issues

Experience:

TATA STEEL Ongoing

Reliance Industries Ltd Aug 2016 - May 2022

Pass Section Officer Apr 2022 - May 2022

 Responsible for managing smooth operations of the Pass section and managing footfall of 1000+ on daily basis.

- Ensuring smooth functioning of all the digital platforms used for the creation of Contractor workers Passes (SCRUM, Genetec, Euronet, PIAM & OMPM)
- Ensuring all compliance in the creation of Passes as per statutory norms & company policy.
- Blacklisting & Watchlisting of individuals as per the policy.
- Liaison with all the stakeholders for a smooth customer experience.

Security Automation Officer

Aug 2017 - Apr 2022

- Monitoring Access control and video surveillance system
- Ensure maximum up-keeping of automation devices in coordination with other stakeholders
- Implementation of new automation projects on the ground
- Conducting Data Analysis & assisting business heads in taking the data-driven decision
- Keeping track of every faulty device and sharing insights with concerns
- Assisting Intelligence and vigilance team for case investigations
- Conducting RCA of faulty or damaged devices
- Conduct testing of new or purposed technologies: ANPR, VA Cameras
- Ensuring authorised man & vehicle movement at the site by eagle eye & alarm monitoring
- Assisting JSOC in emergency incident handling and investigations

https://bit.lv/Join2AJ-Google

Email Me: Ajay Kumar

- Incident Handling & Emergency response
- Handling Gate operations & Conducting random checks
- Conducting training sessions and mock drills to enhance the skills and preparedness of security staff
- Ensuring smooth man, material and vehicular movement
- Facilitating VIP or government officials' movement
- Conducting ground investigations & sharing insights with SOC
- Liaison with all stakeholders for smooth security operations.

Certificates:

- Certified in operation & maintenance of Energized Fence System- A1 Fence
- Certification of Competent Patrolling Officer (RIL)
- Certificate of MySQL Essential Training
- Certificate in Basic Python course
- Certification in COVID-19 Contact Tracing
- NCC 'C' Certification from 26 KAR BN in Army wing

Skills:

- Good knowledge of PHP, MySQL and basic understanding of Python Language
- Monitor, detect, log, troubleshoot and ensure smooth actions on events and alarms
- Hands-on experience with Euronet, PIAM and Genetec Security Systems for ACS & VSS
- Troubleshooting and rectification of Security automation devices
- Ensuring Building and gate system implementation and maintenance on the ground
- Case investigations and Liason with other stakeholders

Education:

SURESH GYAN VIHAR UNIVERSITY, JAIPUR* [MCA: 2017-2020]
KLS GOGTE COLLEGE OF COMMERCE, BELGAUM [BCA: 2012-2015]
KENDRIYA VIDYALAYA [10-12: 2010-2012]

Declaration:

I do hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge

Place: Jamnagar, Gujarat [Ajay Kumar]

Date: 19 May 2022

https://bit.ly/Join2AJ-Google

Email Me: Ajay Kumar